SOHAM DUTTA

Front-End / Web Developer

CONTACT

xzoham@gmail.com

(917)-855-9843

Brooklyn, NY 👂

https://www.linkedin.com/in/soham-dut

:a-ny 🗂

sohamdutta.com

EDUCATION

Full Stack Academy Bootcamp 553 hours of full-stack web development coursework March 2020 - June 2020 New York, NY

> Long Island University Biology / Pre-Pharmacy June 2016 - June 2019 Brooklyn, NY

> > **Awards**

Honors Society

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript Typescript HTML5 CSS / SCSS / SASS GraphQL

Libraries

React.js GatsbyJS Redux jQuery

> Axios Node.js

PROFILE

I am a Front-End / Web Developer with 3+ years of industry experience working for FieldRoutes and ServiceTitan, as well as freelancing with clients directly to develop their dream websites. Passionate about aesthetics and blending the art of design with programming. Experienced in working with a team to design, develop, test, and deliver pixel perfect and responsive web applications on a deadline. I enjoy solving problems and finding new ways to optimize performance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

ServiceTitan

February 2022 - November 2023 / Remote

- Migrated existing CMS from Kentico to Strapi whilst optimizing and updating all components.
- Performed debugging and troubleshooting of applications using JIRA.
- Wrote detailed technical documentation outlining system architecture, coding conventions and best practices.
- Implemented agile development practices across multiple projects, ensuring timely delivery of high-quality solutions.
- Implemented software components to automate manual processes.
- Built pixel perfect components using Javascript, SCSS, and HTML, on the React framework, based off of Adobe XD designs.
- Built the architecture of a SaaS application using React, Gatsby, and GraphQL.

Front End Developer

FieldRoutes

May 2021 - February 2022 / Remote

- Built a scalable templating software with over 50 different themes using React, Gatsby, GraphQL, and a headless CMS (Kentico & Strapi) for clients to deploy customizable websites in minutes.
- Overhauled legacy code base to a modern framework using React, Gatsby, GraphQL, and Kentico as one of the first developers on the team with React and Javascript experience.
- Executed software build and release processes.
- Wrote technical documentation for users and colleagues regarding system architecture and development process.
- Researched and implemented emerging technologies and best practices in software engineering.
- Implemented third-party API's into existing applications for additional functionality.
- Led the architecture of a SaaS application using React, Gatsby, and GraphQL.

Frameworks

React.js GatsbyJS jQuery JestJS

Additional Technologies Used

Adobe XD
Headless CMS (Kentico & Strapi)
Gatsby Cloud
Jira
MongoDB
PostgreSQL
Context API
React Hooks

Full-Stack Developer

Freelance Web Development

September 2020 - May 2021 / Brooklyn, NY

- Designed and developed web pages for local small businesses and clients Using React, Javascript, Typescript, SCSS, GraphQL, Headless CMS, and Netlify to manage the creation and deployment of sites.
- Worked with clients in the process of UI/UX design.
- Created scaleable architecture and efficient queries and trained clients on implementing changes using a CMS.
- Developed pixel perfect and responsive websites.